# 哈喽 大家好
Hello, everybody.
# 最近我买了这个螃蟹
I recently bought some crabs.
# 现在不是中秋节过完了之后吃螃蟹的时间吗
Isn't it the best time to eat crabs after the Mid-Autumn Festival?
# 四伯爷还没吃过螃蟹噶
Uncle has never eaten this kind of crab before.
# 没吃过
Never had one.
# 我老爸倒是吃过
My dad had it before.
# 我四伯跟我伯娘从来没吃过这个大闸蟹
My auntie and my uncle have never eaten this hairy crab before.
# 这个30元钱一只
This is 30 yuan each.
# 这个公的只要15元钱
The male one is only 15 yuan.
# 就比母的要便宜一半
It's half the price of a female.
# 四伯爷你晓得为什么要便宜点不哦
Do you know why male ones come at cheaper price, Uncle?
# 不晓得
I don't know.
# 因为母的（螃蟹）里黄更多 公的里面没有什么黄
Because there's more crab roe in the female, and there's not much in the male.
# 然后我还在网上买了这个
And I also bought this online.
# 这个就稍微高端一点
This is more high-end.
# 好大
Very big
# 哎呀 这个都跑掉了
Oh, the rope is all loose.
# 这个是品牌的啊
It's from top-end brand.
# 这个你猜好多钱一个四伯爷
Guess how much it costs for one, uncle?
# 这个可能是几十块钱一个嘛
It's probably a few dozen yuan each?
# 也是几十噶
A few dozen?
# 嗯
Hmm.
# 这个200多块钱一个
It's actually over 200 yuan each.
# 200多块钱一个安
Over 200 yuan?
# 嗯
Hmm.
# 你的这个东西这么贵买来咋子哦
Why do you pay so much for this?
# 就是买给你们尝哈看
I'm just buying it for you guys to try.
# 主要尝哈这个味道噶
You have to taste this.
# 这是毛
This is hair.
# 吃有啥子吃头嘛
What's the difference between?
# 我还买了这个蟹8件
I also bought those tools for eating this crab.
# 这个我们虽然是农民但是也要追求一下这个
Although we're farmers, but we also want to try this.
# 这个叫啥子安
What's this called?
# 优雅的吃大闸蟹
Eating hairy crabs gracefully
# 所以我买了这个
That's why I bought those.
# 这个安
This.
# 这个
This one.
# 这个是螃蟹放在上面敲的
Put the crab on top of it.
# 给它轻轻地敲一下
Give it a little knock.
# 我昨天已经拍了一个（视频）这个怎么吃
I already shot one video yesterday on how to eat this crab.
# 这个过程这个程序已经拍好了但是还没有更
The process has been filmed but not update yet.
# 现在每一个视频我都会在没有更新之前
Now before every new dish video I will make.
# 先做给父母家人尝一下
I'll make it for my parents and family first.
# 吐泡泡是说明它是活的
The bubbles mean it's alive.
# 这样呀
I see.
# 嗯
Hmm.
# 你看嘛
You see?
# 这个像下雨一样你听嘛
The sound is like rain. Take a listen.
# 嗯
Hmm.
# 是不是 四伯爷
Isn't that right, Uncle?
# 你听嘛这样子
That's what it sounds like.
# 它是嚓嚓嚓的
It's cha-cha-cha.
# 这样子你看一边放一个
Put one on each side of ear like this.
# 一会儿你就要睡着
You'll be fall in asleep soon.
# 我们做这个很简单的就只要切一点姜葱就可以了
It's easy to cook this, just chop some ginger and scallions.
# 姜葱
Ginger and scallion.
# 姜切成片放在水里面 葱也放在水里面
Slice the ginger and put it in the water, the same for the scallions.
# 然后在水里面再放一点料酒或者是黄酒
Then add a little more cooking wine or Shaoxing cooking wine.
# 然后再放蒸格把蟹蒸熟
Then put the steamer on to steam the crabs.
# 是嘛200多一个
Over 200 yuan each.
# 不关事我买给你吃
It's okay. I bought it for you.
# 开玩笑
Be serious.
# 我买给你吃
I will buy more for you.
# 要的啊
Yes.
# 好了 现在我们这个就要准备蒸它了
Okay, now we're going to steam them.
# 我们这个螃蟹蒸的时候把它翻过来放
When we steam the crab, turn it upside down.
# 水开了再下
Wait until the water is boiling.
# 然后这个三两的蟹我们一般蒸16分钟
And we usually steam this crab for 16 minutes.
# 这个一定要蒸熟
This must be steamed thoroughly.
# 蒸得不熟生的吃了容易出问题
If it's undercooked, raw carb can cause problems.
# 四伯爷帮我端哈这个嘛 我拿这个过去
Uncle, help me with this. I'll take this over there.
# 那这个（螃蟹）洗不洗安
Are you going to wash this or not?
# 要要要 刷哈
Yes, yes. Scrub-clean.
# 可以了
That's it.
# 拿帕子来嘛
You need a towel.
# 不用
No, it's okay.
# 哦哟 蒸红了
Oh, it's steaming red.
# 这个蒸得很红的
This one's steaming red.
# 嗯
Hmm.
# 这个因为有大的所以我们蒸了18分钟
This one took us 18 minutes to steam because it is quite big.
# 这小的其实16分钟就已经熟了
This smaller one's actually done in 16 minutes.
# 整都整不好来吃
They seem to be hard to eat.
# 先把绳子剪了
Cut the rope first.
# 这个很简单倒是整得来的
It's easy, it will work.
# 等它冷一会我给你敲一个出来
I'll shell one out for you when it's cooler.
# 跟它敲核桃样噶
Just like the walnut.
# 嗯 敲核桃
Yeah. Cracking walnuts.
# 这个小的是我在菜市场买的这个花绳
I bought those smaller ones with floral rope at the market.
# 这个白绳子的是品牌的就是贵的
Those with white rope is from top brand. It's expensive.
# 我抓住给它一转
Grabbed it and gave it a spin.
# 看这儿
Look at this.
# 哎呀 好烫哦
Ouch, it's hot.
# 我给你弄 四伯爷
I'll do it for you, Uncle.
# 轻轻就弄出来的
It was easy.
# 一行做一行 凉糕服豆子糖
The right tool is for the right job.
# 这个东西给它一戳就出来了
Just use this thing give it a poke and the meat will come out.
# 是啊 工具拿来就是这样用的啊
Yeah, that's what tools are for.
# 这样蘸 蘸了就可以吃了是不
You dip it and eat it, right?
# 嗯
Hmm.
# 蘸来就吃了
Dip it in and eat it.
# 哟
Hmm.
# 怎么样嘛
How's it going?
# 吃完了之后还回甜回甜的
It's even sweeter aftertaste.
# 一个是它的心 一个是它的胃
The heart and the stomach.
# 是不能要嘞
Are not eatable.
# 看 这坨
Look at this.
# 这坨不能要噶
Can't have this one.
# 嗯 这坨不能吃
Can't eat that.
# 你尝哈这个黄嘛四伯爷
Try this one, Uncle.
# 我把这个给你抠出来
Let me get this out for you.
# 这儿
Here
# 拿着
This.
# 怎么样
how was it?
# 好吃 这个东西好吃
This is good. This is so good.
# 好吃噶
Delicious right.
# 嗯 它（蟹黄）比你这个脚好吃点
Well, it tastes even better than the legs.
# 徒弟就先等一下啊 两个徒弟先等一下
Apprentices, just wait a moment... two apprentices.
# 先把老人伺候好了再说
Let me take care of the elders first.
# 我看着就好了
I'll just watch.
# 你先看一下啊
Take a look first.
# 我都没吃上你不着急
I haven't even eaten yet. You guys shouldn't in a hurry.
# 我伯娘是因为感冒了她不能吃这个
My aunt can't eat this because she has a cold.
# 这个有点寒性
The crab are not good for cold.
# 等你感冒好了
When you get over your cold.
# 重新给你买下来整给你吃哈 四伯娘
I'll buy you some new one to eat, Auntie.
# 我们今天本来是想文吃的
We were supposed to eat gracefully today (use the tools)...
# 结果现在都动武了 大家都等不及了
And now we all eating by hand. Everyone can't wait.
# 好 你先吃这个嘛吃到嘛你
Okay, you eat this first.
# 好 我现在要试一下贵的怎么样
Okay, I'm going to try the expensive ones now.
# 反正我们试了这个小的很好吃
We tried those smaller one and it was delicious.
# 直接看里面吧
Just look inside.
# 看一下怎么样
Let's see how it goes.
# 心慌得很
I'm a bit nervous.
# 这个还是有一点点黄
It's also got some crab roe in it.
# 这个我先尝一下啊 尝一下怎么样
I'll try this first. Try the taste.
# 吃东西都要学
You have to learn how to eat it.
# 是要学啊吃这些东西
You right about learning how to eat these things.
# 你不学不得行
You can't do it without learning.
# 我觉得这个200多块钱的
I think the one's over 200 yuan...
# 可能是因为这个天气问题吧
Maybe it's because of the weather.
# 好像还
It seems...
# 还不如我们30元钱这个好吃
It's may even not as good as the one we paid 30 yuan for.
# 这个实话实说啊
That's the truth.
# 可能是因为这个雨水
Maybe it's because of the rain.
# 太充足了
There is too much rain.
# 四伯爷还是这个便宜的好吃点
Uncle, I think the cheaper one and tastes better.
# 嗯
Hmm.
# 来嘛漆二娃
Come on, QiErWa.
# 王介平来吃螃蟹了
Wong Jieping come here for the crab.